<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Open spending</title>
    <link>http://open-spending.test/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Open spending</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>pl-PL</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 17:01:05 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://open-spending.test/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Open Spending EU Coalition Guidance on the Transparency of the RRF Spending</title>
      <link>http://open-spending.test/posts/guidance_rrf_transparency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 17:01:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://open-spending.test/posts/guidance_rrf_transparency/</guid>
      <description>Transparent and open RRF spending is attainable and realistic. To support the European Commission and Member States in establishing the right mechanisms for this, the Open Spending EU Coalition has come up with concrete, practical recommendations. These recommendations focus on exactly what should be published proactively, and how this information can be published to facilitate multi-stakeholder participation and monitoring.
Our guide is designed for all such scenarios, providing recommendations which can form the basis of a new open spending initiative and/or serve to inform strengthening of pre-existing transparency. The document is open to public consultations. We welcome any feedback by adding a comment in the text by 20th December 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Spending EU Coalition Calls on Poland and Hungary to Ensure Transparency of RRF Spending</title>
      <link>http://open-spending.test/posts/calls_on_poland_and_hungary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 13:06:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://open-spending.test/posts/calls_on_poland_and_hungary/</guid>
      <description>The Open Spending EU Coalition today urged Poland and Hungary to include strong guarantees of transparency in their National Plans under the Recovery and Resilience Facility Fund (RRF) and called on the European Commission to ensure that such transparency is clearly stated before approving the plans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis finds EU’s Recovery and Resilience Facility spending at risk due to lack of transparency</title>
      <link>http://open-spending.test/posts/analysis_finds_eu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 13:03:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://open-spending.test/posts/analysis_finds_eu/</guid>
      <description>Open Spending EU Coalition analysed the transparency, reporting and accountability measures put in place to ensure open and accountable implementation of the Recovery and Resilience Facility national plans of 22 EU member states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access Info Europe: 5 solutions for local governments to prevent and fight corruption !!!</title>
      <link>http://open-spending.test/posts/access_info_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 13:00:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://open-spending.test/posts/access_info_europe/</guid>
      <description>Access Info together with its partners in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anticorruptiontoolkit.eu/&#34;&gt;pan-European project ACT!&lt;/a&gt; have presented a range of technical solutions for local governments to increase their levels of transparency and prevent any risk of corruption, covering the following areas: whistleblowing, access to information, open data in public procurement, transparency of meetings involving public officials and risk analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCP: Buy open, buy fast: how open contracting helped Lithuania’s Coronavirus response</title>
      <link>http://open-spending.test/posts/ocp_buy_open_buy_fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 16:33:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://open-spending.test/posts/ocp_buy_open_buy_fast/</guid>
      <description>The move allowed the government, civil society and journalists to investigate spending and solve problems. Based on this success, Lithuania is now moving to put open data and open government at the heart of its new procurement reforms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
